# Georgios Vavouliotis | Curriculum Vitae

Travessera de Les Corts 37, 08028 - Barcelona - Spain

☑ gvavou5@gmail.com • ② gvavou5.github.io • in georgios-vavouliotis

#### **Profile**

I earned my diploma on Electrical and Computer Engineering from the National Technical University of Athens (NTUA). Currently, I am a 3rd year Ph.D. student in Computer Science at Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC) and Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS). My supervisors are Dr. Marc Casas Guix from BSC-CNS and Dr. Lluc Alvarez from UPC. Moreover, I collaborate with Prof. Daniel A. Jiménez from Texas A&M University and Prof. Boris Grot from the University of Edinburgh. My research aims at designing microarchitectural prediction/prefetching mechanisms that inherently use machine learning algorithms. In particular, I look at more intelligent predictors/prefetchers for the cache and the TLB hierarchy.

# Areas of (Research) Interest

Computer Architecture, High Performance Computing (HPC) Systems, Machine Learning for Computer Architecture; identifying and exploiting the predictability of programs to design microarchitectural prefetching/prediction mechanisms for the cache and the TLB hierarchy, improving the cache/TLB management, and leverage machine learning algorithms to design intelligent microarchitectural components.

## **Education**

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC)

Barcelona

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.)

Leveraging Artificial Intelligence Algorithms for Hardware Prediction

September 2018-now

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

Diploma on Electrical & Computer Engineering, 300 ECTS, GPA: 8.9/10

2012-March 2018

#### Academic Directions.....

- Computer Systems & Software
- Computer Networks and Networks Security
- Signal Processing, Automatic Control and Robotics

Diploma Thesis.....

Performance Analysis of TLB Prefetching Mechanisms, GPA: 10/10

General Lyceum, Chalkida, Greece

Chalkida

Apolytirion, Top 0.2% in National Qualification Exams, GPA: 19.5/20

2009-2012

# Research Experience

## **Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)**

Barcelona

Researcher at Computer Architecture & Operating Systems Group (CAOS) September 2018-now

## National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

Research Student at Computer Systems Laboratory (CSLab)

February 2018-July 2018

# **Participation in Projects**

### SOW 5.3 - Intel and BSC-CNS Collaboration

Barcelona

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

September 2018-now

High Performance Computing VII

Barcelona

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

September 2018-now

#### **Publications**

- [1] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Goumas Georgios, "Performance Analysis of TLB Prefetching Mechanisms". Book of my diploma thesis.
- [2] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Daniel A. Jimenez, Marc Casas Guix, *Cost-Effective Instruction TLB Prefetching*. Second Young Architect Workshop (YArch 2020). In conjunction with The 25th ACM International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems (ASPLOS 2020), Lausanne.
- [3] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Vasileios Karakostas, Konstantinos Nikas, Nectarios Koziris, Daniel A. Jimenez, Marc Casas Guix, *Exploiting Page Table Locality for Agile TLB Prefetching*. To appear in the 48th International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA).

#### **Technical Reviewer for Conferences**

18th ACM International Conference on Computing Frontiers (CF'21)

<sup>o</sup> Sub-reviewer

**IEEE Supercomputing Conference (SC'21)** 

Sub-reviewer

# **Teaching Experience**

Private Tutor Athens

During my Diploma I was giving private lectures to:

2013-2018

**Undergraduate students of Computer Science Department** 

C programming, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, Automatic Control

High school students

Mathematics, Physics

Lab Assistant at National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

C programming

2013-2017

# **Seminars and Training Courses**

#### **Summer Schools**

Participation in accredited Summer Schools (certification provided)

## **HPC Architectures for Artificial Intelligence and Dedicated Applications**

Provided by **ACM-Europe**, 17 - 24 July 2019

#### Seminars

Participation in accredited seminars (certification provided)

# Introduction to Big Data & Practical Data Analytics for Solving Real World Problems

Provided by **PACT BSC-CNS**, February 2021

#### Introduction to Heterogenous Memory Usage

Provided by **PACT BSC-CNS**, February 2019

#### **Online Courses (MOOCs)**

Ourses offered by accredited universities and training programs (certification provided)

## **Machine Learning**

- Provided by Stanford University (Prof. Andrew Ng), May 2018 July 2018, GPA: 10/10
  - · Supervised Learning (Regression Models, SVMs, NN)
  - · Unsupervised Learning (Clustering, Dimensionality Reduction)

#### **Advanced Programming with Python**

Provided by Mathesis Online Platform, March 2018 - April 2018, GPA: 10/10

- · Object Oriented Programming
- · Data Storage (sqlite3, pickle, JSON)
- · Graphic Interface Programming and Game Development

## **Technical and Personal skills**

#### Programming Languages:

- Advanced knowledge: C
- Working knowledge: C++, Python, Matlab, Assembly (8085, 8086, AVR), SML/NJ, HTML

#### Tools:

- Advanced knowledge: Unix Bash, LATEX, SVN
- Working knowledge: Git, CACTI, MS Office

#### Simulators:

- Advanced knowledge: ChampSim
- Working knowledge: Gem5

#### o General Business Skills:

- Ability to work with a team
- Very good presentation skills
- Able to write well organized and structured reports

#### **Honors and Awards**

#### 2019 FPI Doctoral Fellowship

Funded by Spanish Government (MINECO)

**Barcelona** 

2019-2022

Mathematics Award - National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Excellent marks in all mathematical courses during the first two (2) years.

**Athens** 2014

"The Great Moment of Education" Eurobank EFG Scholarship

Chalkida

O Highest rank in National Qualifications Exams in my school

2012

## **Affiliations**

o Affiliated PhD student in HiPEAC (European Network of Excellence on High Performance and Embedded Arcitecture and Compilation)

# Languages

- Greek (Native)
- Italian (Beginner)
- English (B2 (FCE, KPG))Spanish (Beginner)

# Personal Interests and extra-curricular activity

Cooking

Basketball

Writing

Challenges

Travelling

Cinema

## References

References available upon request.